&gt；&gt；Kyle：在这些基本类型中，我们应该有一些特殊值
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Within those primitive types there are special values that we should
注意。
pay attention to.
而且有很多这样的人，但是
And there are a number of them but
我想把我们的注意力集中在两个特殊的价值观上。
I wanna focus our attention on two specific special values.
这些问题出现的频率比我们希望的要高得多，或者至少有一些
These are ones that crop up much more often than we would like, or at least some
其中，至少有一个比我们希望的更频繁地出现。
of them, at least one of them crops up more often than we would like.
对它们的认识将有助于我们避免虫子和
And awareness of both of them is gonna help us avoid bugs and
在某些情况下，甚至可以从我们的JavaScript语言中获得更多功能。
in some cases, even get more power out of our JavaScript language.
所以让我们来看第一个它被称为NaN的，
So let's look at the first one it's referred to as NaN,
这应该是不是数字的首字母缩写。
which is supposedly an acronym for not a number.
从历史上看，这就是它的来源，NaN至少在JavaScript中出现，
Historically, that's where it comes from, NaN comes to us at least in JavaScript,
它是通过IEEE 754规范(数字规范)来实现的。
it comes by way of the IEEE 754 spec, the number spec.
本质上，NaN并不意味着不是一个数字，它本质上意味着
Essentially NaN doesn't mean not a number essentially it means
这个特殊的，我们称之为标记值的值，表示一个无效的数字。
this special what we call sentinel value that indicates an invalid number.
这是一个比提到它不是一个数字更好的心理模型，
That's a much better mental model for it than referring to it is not a number,
我们应该把at称为无效的数字，所以让我们深入研究一下。
we oughta refer to at as an invalid number, so let's dig into that.
我们怎样才能到达像南这样的东西呢？
How do we arrive at something like a Nan?
好的，第一，你可以把代表数字的东西
Well, number one, you can take things that are representations of numbers in
在这种情况下，字符串形式。
string form, in this case.
例如，我现在的年龄是38岁，我可以代表这两者之一
Like for example, my age at the moment is 38, and I can represent that either
正如引用38，或者在本例中，在第1行上，我可以用八进制表示它。
as quote 38 or, in this case, on line 1, I could represent it in octal.
八进制表示是46。
The octal representation being 46.
我不喜欢那个
I don't like that one,
因为这让我听起来老了很多，所以我不想用它。
cuz that makes me sound a lot older so I don't wanna use that.
但是我可以用字符串的形式表示它，然后我有一个数字，比如数字38。
But I can represent it in string form, and then I have a number, like the number 38.
或者我可以引用39号来引用我的下一个年龄。
Or I can do quote 39 to reference my next age.
我不再养猫了，所以当我说我的猫的年龄，并且
I don't own cats anymore, so when I say my cat's age, and
我使用不适用的东西，没有数字可以用来指代它。
I use something like not applicable there's no number to use to refer to that.
让我非常具体和明确地告诉你们，数字0是
And let me be very specific and clear with you the number 0 is
不是您指示缺少有效数值的方式。
not the way you indicate the absence of valid numeric value.
对任何一个数学家来说，数字0绝对是一个重要的数字。
Talk to any math mathematician, the number 0 is absolutely an important number.
这是一个有实质意义的数字。
It is a number that has substance to it.
它在任何方面都是不合适的
It's not appropriate in any way shape or
形式将0视为缺少数值的占位符。
form to think of 0 as being the place holder for absence of numeric value.
在数学上没有意义，在程序上也没有意义。
Doesn't make sense mathematically and doesn't make sense programatically.
那么我们应该用什么号码呢？
So what number should we use?
嗯，这就是为什么IEEE在定义特殊的位模式时会这样做
Well, that's why IEEE did when they defined the special bit pattern that
表示这是我们指示的数字。
represents this is the number that we indicate.
这不是一个有效的数字，我无法对n/a执行任何操作。
It's not a valid number, I can't do anything with n/a.
基本上不存在n/a的数制
There's essentially no number system where n/a
是一个数字[笑]的有效表示，除非你发明了一个。
is a valid representation of a number [LAUGH] unless you invented one.
所以我们拿回了Nan，我们拿回了无效号码。
So we get NaN back, we get the invalid number back.
顺便说一下，当你用一个无效的号码做事情时，
And by the way, when you do things with an invalid number,
即使是看起来很疯狂的事情，比如减去字符串，
even things that seem crazy, like subtracting strings,
你会拿回无效的号码。
you're gonna get invalid number back.
第4行，我的年龄减去，然后是一条字符串，就像我儿子的年龄，
Line 4, my age minus, and then a string, like my son's age,
这实际上没有任何意义，至少在编程上没有意义。
doesn't actually make any sense, not programatically, anyway.
但是JavaScript有一种我们经常掩饰的思考方式。
But JavaScript has a way of thinking about this that we often gloss over.
特别是，JavaScript考虑到这一点，因为负运算符需要数字，
In particular, JavaScript thinks about this as the minus operator needs numbers,
它只为数字定义。
it's only defined for numbers.
当你给它一个不是数字的东西时，
When you give it something that is not a number,
&gt；&gt；Kyle：然后它说，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Then it says,
我需要把它变成一个数字。
I need to turn it into a number.
这就是我们将讨论的，当我们进入强制的一小部分。
That's what we'll talk about when we get into coercion in a little bit.
所以，它改变了，引用，我儿子的年龄，
So, it turns the, quote, my son's age,
顺便说一句，他8岁，我儿子的年龄，
which by the way he's 8, my son's age,
它将他的年龄，字符串转化为NaN值。
it turns his age, that string into the NaN value.
所以当我说我的年龄减去，我实际上是在说我的年龄减去NaN，并且
So when I say my age minus, I'm actually saying my age minus NaN, and
NaN和任何其他数学运算都是NaN，因为它是无效的。
NaN with any other mathematical operation is always NaN, cuz it's invalid.
所以NaN一直在传播。
So NaN sort of propagates all the way out.
你永远不能做任何事情，包括NaN和
There's nothing that you can ever do that includes a NaN and
产生除NaN以外的任何结果，无论如何，在数学上都是如此。
results in anything other than a NaN, mathematically anyway.
顺便说一句，你会注意到即使我的猫的年龄是NaN，
And by the way, you'll notice that even though my cat's age is NaN,
它不等于自身，或者至少根据三重等于运算符，
it is not equal to itself, or at least according to the triple equals operator,
它并不等于它自己。
it's not equal to itself.
许多人喜欢相信三重等于运算符告诉您
Many people like to believe that the triple equals operator tells you
真相，但我有消息告诉你三重等于运算符的谎言。
the truth, but I have news for you the triple equals operator lies.
它告诉你这两个东西是不相等的。
It tells you that those two things are not equal.
它这样做的原因并不是因为Brendan Eich那天疯了。
And the reason it does that is not because Brendan Eich was crazy that day.
它这样做是因为IEEE说NAN彼此不平等。
It does that because IEEE said NaNs are not equal to each other.
事实上，NaN是存在的唯一价值，至少在JavaScript中是这样，
As a matter of fact, NaN is the only value in existence, at least in JavaScript,
它是唯一没有我们称为身份属性的值，
it's the only value that does not have what we call the identity property,
意思是它不等于它自己。
meaning it is not equal to itself.
这是唯一正确的价值。
It's the only value where that is true.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：未定义，未定义是否相同？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Undefined, undefined's the same?
&gt；&gt；Kyle：undefined绝对等于自身。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Undefined is absolutely equal to itself.
NaN是唯一不等于自身的值。
NaN is the only value that is not equal to itself.
所以我们需要一些方法来确定，因为三重等于对我们撒谎，
So we need some way to determine because triple equals lies to us,
我们需要一些方法来确定该值是否实际上是NaN。
we need some way to determine if the value is in fact NaN.
JavaScript最初附带了一个名为isNaN的实用程序，
And JavaScript shipped originally with a utility called isNaN,
当我们将数字之类的东西传递给它时，我们正确地得到了false。
which when we pass a thing like a number to it we correctly get false.
当我们通过一个实际上，合法的是NaN的东西时，我们就得到了真。
And when we pass a thing that actually, legitimately is NaN, we get true.
看起来很棒，直到我们看到第10行，当我们通过一些
Seems great until we look at line 10 when we pass in something that
绝对不是一个数字，字符串我儿子的年龄。
is definitely not a number, the string my son's age.
但让我问你一个问题，这不是一个数字，我们同意这一点，但是
But let me ask you the question, it's not a number, we agree with that, but
是NaN值吗？
is it the NaN value?
绝对不是。
Most definitely not.
那么为什么我们仍然是真实的呢？
So why do we still get true?
成为现实的历史原因，是因为出于某种原因，isNaN
The historical reason for getting true, is because for some reason, the isNaN
实用程序在检查数值是否为NaN之前将值强制为数字。
utility coerces values to numbers before it checks for them to be NaN.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：所以，它将强制字符串我儿子的年龄为一个数字
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So, it's gonna coerce the string my son's age to a number and
猜猜它会强迫它的号码是多少？
guess what number it's gonna coerce it to?
NaN值，所以它当然会返回true。
The NaN value, so of course it's gonna back true.
现在，猜猜我怎么知道它能做到这一点。
Now, guess how I know that it does that.
我看了说明书，说明书非常清楚地写着，强迫它到一个数字。
I read the spec, and the spec very clearly says, coerce it to a number.
在初始JavaScript中发生错误后一段时间，
Sometime after that mistake happened in initial JavaScript,
他们觉得这不是个好主意。
they decided that's a bad idea.
因此，在ES6中，我们得到了一个更好的实用程序，Number.isNan实用程序。
So with ES6, we got a better utility, the Number.isNan utility.
并且Number.isNan挑衅地告诉我们，它肯定是NaN值，或者不是。
And that Number.isNan tells us defiantly for sure it's the NaN value or it's not.
换句话说，它对我们没有任何强制作用。
In other words it doesn't do any coercion for us.
它明确地告诉我们这是号码。
It tells us specifically it's the number.
所以就像回到你关于NaN是什么的问题上？
So like going back to your question about what is NaN?
好吧，如果我做一个数值运算
Well, if I do a numeric operation and
我返回一个值，我期望返回的类型是什么
I get back a value what type am I expecting back
从每一个数字运算？
from every single numeric operation?
我在等一个数字，对吧？
I'm expecting a number, right?
还记得我说过，NAN是IEEE 754规范的一部分，
And remember I said NaNs are part of the IEEE 754 spec which is
数字表示规范。
a numeric representation specification.
令人费解的是，NaN的类型是数字。
So perplexingly, the type of a NaN is number.
这只是一个无效的号码。
It's just an invalid number.
这就是为什么认为它不是一个数字是不合适的，因为然后你
Which is why it's not appropriate to think of it as not a number because then you
陷入那怪异不是数字类型的字眼是数字吗？
get into that weirdness the wording of type of not a number is number?
那是因为认为它不是一个数字是错误的，
That's because it's wrong to think of it as not a number,
最好认为它是一个无效的数字。
it's better to think of it as an invalid number.
当然，无效数字的类型肯定是数字。
And of course the type of and invalid number is definitely number.
有人对我说，不，他们不应该做什么，南，别管我做了什么
I have people suggest to me no no no they should have never done NaN nevermind what
我EEE 754说的。
I EEE 754 said.
他们不应该做Nan，我们应该退回一些其他的东西。
They never should have done NaN, we should have returned something else.
真的吗？
Really?
我们应该从数值操作返回什么
What should we return from a numeric operation that's
不会是那种号码吧？
gonna be not of the type number?
我们可以返回undefined，但这不是数字。
We could return back undefined, but that's not numeric.
这是一个糟糕的想法，给开发人员一些作为诱饵和切换的东西。
That's a terrible idea, to give developers something that's a bait and switch.
我们也许可以返回空，糟糕的主意。
We could maybe return back null, terrible idea.
我们可以返回错误的，糟糕的想法，我们可以返回，呃，-1。
We could return back false, terrible idea, we could return back, ugh, -1.
这是古老的，历史的，当你做一些类似索引的事情，和
This is old, historical, when you do something like index of, and
它在您的字符串或数组中找不到东西。
it can't find something in your string or array.
因为在过去的C时代，你只能返回数字，它们不是IEEE754。
Because in the old C days, you could only return numbers, and they weren't IEEE 754.
那么他们能找到的唯一的数字是什么
So what was the only number they could come up
用来表示没有找到它或无效的搜索吗？
with to represent didn't find it or invalid search?
他们选择了-1，这对他们来说就像40年前一样好。
They chose -1, which was fine for them like 40 years ago.
我不知道为什么我们在JavaScript中采用它，但我们做到了。
I don't know why we adopt it in a JavaScript but we did.
所以我们有一些返回-1的API，当更合适的时候
So we have some of our APIs that return back -1, when the more appropriate
我们在语言中拥有的数字，为了表示，我没有发现它是NaN。
number that we had in the language, to represent I didn't find it as NaN.
如果你在设计一个系统，你想回来
If you're designing a system, and you wanna return and
有人希望得到一个号码，而你想要向他们发出信号，没有有效的
somebody expects to get a number and you wanna signal to them there's no valid
数字对我来说，只有一个值是有意义的。
number for me to give there is only one value that makes any sense at all.
你应该把Nan还回去。
You should return the NaN.
但比起我在这张单子上的其他抱怨，更多的是什么时候
But more than any other complaint that I have on this list is when
人们试图以某种方式将0称为NaN的占位符。
people try to refer to 0 as somehow a placeholder for NaN.
我们会回到这一点，强迫，稍等片刻。
And we'll come back to this and coercion and just a moment.
所以NaN，它是一个数字，它是无效的数字，并且
So NaN, it is a number, and it is the invalid number, and
它将出现在您的程序中，而不是可能，它会发生，并且
it is going to occur in your programs, not maybe, it will, and
您应该适当地测试它。
you should be testing for it appropriately.
否则，你有错误，你不能处理那些错误。
Otherwise, you have bugs and you're not handling those bugs.